and you build muscle without protein no
no you can't in fact their arguments
maybe you can't even live without
protein it is one of the essential
macronutrients it's the hottest
macronutrient to get it is the most
expensive and the least convenient way
to get a macronutrient like when you're
out and about especially you go to a
corner store it's not hard to find some
carbs and fat the protein unless you're
counting around some chicken breasts in
your pocket it's it's very hard to get a
high protein diet or even an adequate
protein diet but fortunately whey
protein is here to help and so because
it is such a common supplement and they
line the shelves of every supplement
store and it is for the newcomer and for
the experienced athlete like it can be
so hard to decide if any of them is
better than anything else on the market
we have tried dozens and dozens and
dozens of them to land on this list of
the best whey proteins on the market so
stick around we're going to make you an
expert now before I go on I do need to
make it clear that I'm not a doctor I'm
a medical professional so if you are
planning to make any big changes or any
little changes to your dietary regimen
supplement Arrangement exercise regimen
make sure you talk to a qualified
medical professional to ensure that I
think it's going to conflict with like
medications maybe taking or your
individual history or just your
individual personality type with that
said let's get into our topic now I've
all the way projects on the market our
absolute favorite is Wolverines way
isolate we've got a lot of reasons for
basically it's a nice stripped down
product that doesn't give you anything
you don't need and only has extra
ingredients that might provide some
benefits got a lot of protein per
calorie because they use whey isolate
which is very low in fat and
carbohydrates plus it may digest more
effectively as well due to some extra
enzymes have added in here so I just
said whey isolate though and you might
be wondering what is way isolate and
what are the other kinds of way and what
is whey protein in the first place I'm
gonna answer all those questions then
we're gonna jump back into the list
[Music]
so to quickly answer some really
frequently asked questions about these
kinds of products whey is one of the
proteins in Dairy right there's whey and
casein in the production process for
cheese you take the casein away from the
Whey tasting this used to make cheese
wait we used to throw it out until we
realize it's a really really good
quality protein it's actually the most
bioavailable protein on the earth which
means it absorbs the best out of any of
the protein you can find there are three
kinds of way generally speaking the
fastest way concentrate that's the most
basic form it has the most carbs and fat
in it but it's also the cheapest you
also got way isolate after that which
has been processed in such a way that it
removes most if not all of the carbs and
lactose and sugar and fat then there's a
hydrolicit which has some enzymes added
to it to break it down even further in
such a way that it absorbs faster than
any other whey protein however it does
taste a bit more bitter it is a lot more
expensive and there's benefits they're
not really very applicable or practical
for the average person that kind of
stuff is really really important if
you're like an Olympic level athlete
most folks are going to be just fine
with weight concentrate isolate and
that's all we're going to want to pay
for as well when should you take whey
protein to the question we get asked a
lot as well the answer is whenever you
feel like it's just protein right you
can have it with any meal you have as a
side for any meal you can have it before
workout after workout in the middle of a
workout there used to be a very
pervasive myth that there is a
post-workout anabolic window during
which after workout you have to Sprint
and consume some liquid protein as fast
as humanly possible that's not really
the case what actually matters the most
at the end of the day is your total
calories your total protein
carbohydrates and fat when you eat stuff
isn't very important and how quickly
after a workout you eat isn't super
important either it's the total package
of calories and macronutrients that
matters the most that said if you have
an empty stomach before a workout many
people find that having some protein
powder beforehand can be helpful at
giving you some extra energy try to
workout not because it's a stimulant but
because it provides some amino acids
into your bloodstream it helps to retain
muscle and can this generally make you
feel like it can last a little bit
longer otherwise time timing isn't a
massive deal with these sorts of shakes
with an empty stomach though they can be
pretty useful to help you get through a
workout the last question to quickly
cover is how much whey protein to take
there's not really a maximum amount but
a lot of people think there's a minimum
amount of in the area of 20 to 25 grams
of protein that's because there's amino
acid called leucine in Whey Protein that
is closely associated with muscle
protein synthesis and there's evidence
to suggest that you want to get a good
two and a half three grams or so in
order to initiate muscle protein
synthesis we're getting a little bit
complicated here and muscle growth has a
lot of other factors involved in it but
still if you want to get let's say the
most effective delivery of whey protein
powder you want to make sure you're
getting yeah a good a good 20 grams or
so just to make sure that your
stimulating muscle protein synthesis all
right so let's get back to our list the
best overall whey protein is the way
isolate from Wolverine which is also our
favorite way I slip because this is wait
I slip as I mentioned the way I swear it
tends to be a lot friendlier on folks
who are sensitive to lactose this one
here also though is totally free of a
lot of components that some people try
to avoid we're not saying these are
officially bad for you or should be
avoided but there's no denying that
there are plenty of people on the market
who try to avoid soy and gluten there
are neither of those in this product and
soy is actually extremely common because
soy lecithin in a protein powder helps
it to like dissolve and mix up a bit
more easily there's nothing wrong with
having a small amount of soy people
worry about estrogen in it there's
nowhere near enough to have any effect
nonetheless if you want to avoid it
there's none in here as mentioned this
is very high in protein per calorie
there are very few extra carbohydrates
and fat here half a gram of fat here on
the chocolate milkshake flavor two grams
of carbohydrates just one gram of sugar
and 26 grams of protein that's a really
impressive profile the last thing I
wanted to mention is that this contains
digestive enzymes which is a really cool
Extra Touch here there is some data to
suggest when you take certain digestive
enzymes with a protein powder they'll
find the amino acids in your bloodstream
they'll appear there more quickly than
if the enzymes weren't there in other
words when you add enzymes to your
protein powder it is quite possible that
it's going to absorb faster and more
effectively than if you haven't and that
just means you know you're getting more
protein for the dollar everyone wants to
absorb what they're paying for right so
this has 10 milligrams of logistic
enzymes papine and protease and yeah
proteases are the ones that help to
break down protein
so that's why this is our favorite way
isolate and our favorite whey protein
powder overall on the market side note
it's absolutely delicious this one
here's a chocolate milkshake flavor and
the honey cinnamon peanut butter flavor
is going to change your life if that's
the one you buy next up on our list we
want to talk about huge supplements huge
way we're really big fans of this
product the cool thing about a huge way
is it actually has a few ingredients
added to it that might potentially make
it a little bit more anabolic so naming
this one the best way for muscle growth
and also the best way for men men tend
to win the game but muscle in the gym
and also this is higher in calories and
some of the other protein powders here
and generally man they tend to weigh
more and they tend to require more
calories in order to gain some muscle so
we call this one the best way protein
for men and for muscle gain what's in it
this one is made with whey concentrate
which as I mentioned has more
carbohydrates and fat than away isolate
but if your goal is muscle gain you are
actually and if you've tried to do it in
real life you'll know this you're trying
to get extra calories throughout the day
getting really low calorie foods and
supplements all the time isn't really
conducive to the goals of gaining muscle
so this one it's not crazy high in
calories but relative to everything else
here for a 23 and a half grams serving
of protein the six grams of
carbohydrates and three grams of fat as
opposed to like the half a gram of fat
and two grams of carbs are getting in
way I slip the six guys are
carbohydrates here the powder that comes
from like lactose and from sugars but
also they've added in some dextrose here
there's an argument to be made that
adding extra dextrose that's going to
have a little bit more of an insulin
Spike and insulin is generally
considered an anabolic hormone there are
some other issues with spiking insulin
yes but in a measured and controlled way
and having it right after a workout is
possible this could potentially help to
increase absorption with that extra
dextrose and that extra little insulin
bump there are two more things I want to
mentioned on this ingredients list
number one there is a little bit of
digestive enzymes in here from papine
which you find in papaya and that is a
protea so that can help with the
absorption it's not as much as in
Wolverine but nonetheless that could be
a pretty cool addition and there's also
lactase which is digestive enzyme that
is often added into products to help to
minimize or reduce digestive discomfort
among those with lactose because this is
way concentrate it does have lactose in
it many people find that lactase helps
to eliminate or reduce the discomfort
from the lactose obviously that depends
on you the degree of sensitivity and the
conversation you have with your doctor
nonetheless it's a nice addition to a
weight concentrate and we always like to
see it in a way concentrate based
products before I go on I forgot to
mention this earlier I know I'm kind of
talking a lot here and if you want to
take in this information at your own
pace we have a written article of this
video that you can pretty easily check
out just go over to Google and write in
bar Bend best way protein powder and
this whole list is going to come right
up so if you want to check out some of
the references some of the signs we're
talking about here or again if you just
want to be able to scroll around and
land on whichever part of this content
you want to land on uh yeah check out
that article all the info is in there
and select the list next up is the best
tasting whey protein powder we're going
with on it for this one and it's a
really interesting Fitness company they
don't just do supplements they do a lot
of like kettlebells and maces and uh
really functional fitness related sort
of apparel and supplements and products
on its way protein here for one is
grass-fed which is interesting that
doesn't really have health benefits when
this is a product that's so low in fat
however it means the cows have been a
little bit happier right it's also all
natural but shockingly it is the best
tasting protein powder this one here is
their vanilla flavor we also really like
their chocolate flavor they call it
mexican chocolate it's got a little bit
of cinnamon in there so that's a little
bit more of a pop a bit more of a Zing
than the average chocolate protein
powder on the market and we find that
it's the one that's always going empty
the quickest at the bobbin office where
massive fans are the tastier another
reason why the flavor is so good on this
is there are two natural sweeteners in
this there's Stevia leaf and monk fruit
extract and also they do make a sincere
attempt to make make it taste a bit more
creamy despite the low-fat content so
there's only two grams of fat in here
but they've found ways to put in MCT
oils and sunflower oils and so on to
help make it taste creamier than you
would imagine for away Iceland and once
again this product is sauce as you can
see big letters on the front grass fed
cows and that makes it our favorite
sustainably sourced protein powder as
well having grass-fed cows is not only
like better for the cows overall health
and also for the fatty acid profile in
their meat and their Dairy it also
simply lowers the carbon footprint and
tends to be better for the local
environment as well so that's not
unusual for on it which is a very kind
of holistic approach to their Fitness
and to their supplements you'll often
find a lot of interesting plant extracts
and natural flavorings and they avoid a
lot of kind of artificial approaches to
Fitness so it makes sense that they
would lean on grass-fed Dairy from New
Zealand no less for their whey protein
isolate here so they've got a really
good fluffy behind the product which
also happens to be the tastiest on the
market as well now let's transition into
another grasshead whey protein which
actually I picked the top spot because
of their filtration and process
successes they use when creating it so
this one here is x-wax it's a pretty
cool company they really are shockingly
low in carbohydrates and fat this is
completely fat free and it has just one
gram of carbohydrate or 25 grams of
protein which is Thoroughly impressive
they also get grass-fed Dairy for this
and they get it from New Zealand as well
which is one of the strictest Nations on
earth when it comes to ensuring and
maintaining Dairy quality so you can
make absolutely sad there's no
antibiotics or like weird hormones or
pesticides or anything like that that
wind up in the dairy on top of that what
we liked about x-wax is the way they
preserve a lot of interesting components
of the way during the processing of the
product so raw way it actually contains
a lot of interesting ingredients we're
talking about like beta lactoglobulin
Glide macro peptide immunoglobins as
well that one I know about that has
links to improved immunity and so on so
a lot of folks like to tout way actually
as a good product to take if you're
feeling under the weather because of
these potential immunity boosting
effects and the micro filtration that
they use when creating this way protein
product here helps to preserve these
important biological nutrients and pass
it on to the consumer so for that reason
we need this the best grass-free whey
protein on the market because they work
so hard to preserve the benefits that
can accompany grass-fed whey next we
want to talk about the best whey protein
for weight loss so that we often find
ourselves recommending cage whey protein
isolate so this is an isolate as
mentioned which means it tends to keep
the calories really low for the amount
of protein you're getting consuming
enough protein is a really important
part of any weight loss protocol to be
clear this is not a weight loss product
and this is not weight loss advice it's
like a separately regulated area of the
FDA but then the last one you're trying
to lose weight you're trying to consume
fewer calories and a lot of people find
they're consuming more protein when
they're trying to lose away it helps to
keep them full and helps them to retain
more muscle mass therefore losing more
fat than when they're losing like muscle
and fat at the same time which can
happen if you're not keeping an eye on
your macronutrients so with the Whey
Protein Isolate like this you're getting
more protein per calorie this is 25
grams of protein per scoop with three
grams of carbohydrates but one gram of
fiber so it's two grams of net
carbohydrates and just half a gram of
fat so basically because this is so
protein dense we found this way isolate
the best pick for weight loss simply
because it minimizes the other
macronutrients to a really good degree
and thereby can help you feel Fuller on
fewer calories next up we're going to
take a bit of a right turn on this and
talk about the best organic protein
powder a lot of people look for organic
whey protein but actually certified by
the USDA is remarkably difficult to find
so in this we're going to mention one of
our favorite Brands is transparent labs
and their organic plant-based protein so
for folks looking for a really good
organic protein powder I would really
recommend checking this one out it's
true that a lot of plant-based protein
powders tend to be really high in
carbohydrates and not actually that high
in protein but this one doesn't matter
to pull off 24 grams of protein per
scoop with three grams of net
carbohydrates and two and a half grams
of fat which is comfortable to what
you're going to get in any whey protein
powder so I really strongly recommend it
if you're concerned about the amino acid
profile of a plant-based protein I would
understand that whey has a really solid
amino acid profile file it's very very
complete plant-based proteins tend not
to be but what they have very smartly
done at transparent Labs is combining
rice and pea protein together and so
when you combine those you get
complementary amino acid profiles and
then explore a complete protein that
really absorbs very very effectively and
is very bioavailable so there really is
vital downside to getting this protein
powder here plus this is actually
certified by the USDA as completely
organic which is going to put a lot of
customers wires to rest so transparent
Labs is our favorite organic protein
powder but our favorite plant-based
protein powder overall is going to be
from Wolverine the reason why this one
stands out it's not organic so that's
why we didn't do at that spot however it
does have also a very similarly
impressive uh macronutrient profile of
22 grams of protein per scoop with three
grams of carbs and two and a half grams
so fat and what we really like is
they've added some extra nutrition here
so while transparent Labs does have a
really considerable amount of iron in it
this product also has a little bit more
iron in addition it's got some niacin
some zinc and some chromium and sodium
all at nice levels as well to provide
some more Complete Nutrition to your
diet so a really good protein per
calorie for a plant-based protein is
also naturally flavored as well with
stevia and some Dutch cocoa natural
flavors that kind of thing just get a
little bit of extra sodium in there to
help with taste but also hydration
because sodium is a really important
component of that and lastly the protein
as opposed to being pee and rice this is
pea and pumpkin so that's really
interesting and pumpkin protein and
pumpkin protein seed do have a very
compelling amino acid profile as well
you don't need to worry about any
missing amino acids with this product
either next up is the best whey protein
for bulking we've got a meal replacement
later on this list that might be an
interesting option but for people who
just want to get really dense protein
who want to make sure they're getting as
much questions as they can for the
calories whether you are a bodybuilder
or someone who's trying to gain as
little fat as possible obviously someone
who simply is trying to find a way to
cram in the last 25 grams of protein and
you're already very high protein diet we
were really impressed with transparent
Labs whey protein eye slip this one here
is grass-fed as well which is always a
nice bonus but otherwise it's really a
very simple strip back formula you're
getting 28 grams of protein for just one
gram of carbohydrates and no fat at all
it is very hard to beat that this is
basically a steamed chicken breast and
then you're going to get grasshead whey
protein isolate in the ingredients with
cargo natural flavor sodium chloride and
Stevia that's it so there's no
artificial flavors or colors or
sweeteners which is pretty rare out
there and there are people especially
they're trying to bulk and gain some
muscle they get concerned about
absorption potentially being affected by
artificial sweeteners the jury is kind
of out on that research it seems
unlikely that it's true but nonetheless
if you want to just like hedge your bed
and make sure you're eating just a
completely clean product I would
consider this a chicken breast in a cup
right like this is as pure protein as
you're about to get so that way I slip
from transparent Labs is a great pick
for bulking if you're just after like I
said like chicken breast in a cup right
if all you're after is something that
has a lot more calories in this and it's
going to healthitude kind of maybe save
some labor when it comes to cramming all
the calories into your day uh we're
gonna talk about the meal replacement
that I mentioned which is also from
transparent Labs so this is the meal
replacement powder from transparent labs
and as a 9 is 220 calories per serving
so you get one big scoop of 56 and a
half grams and in this you get 24 grams
of protein but you're also getting 19
grams of carbs with 5 grams of fiber and
also seven grams of fat this is a much
more robust it's going to taste a bit
better as well because I'm not trying as
hard as they possibly can to cut away
every single other calorie that isn't
protein so a lot of people do prefer to
take meal replacements for that reason
like they do tend to taste a bit better
but on top of that it's also got some
extra added macronutrients here as well
so you're getting 11 of daily iron 17 of
your sodium which remember is great for
hydration the Sports Nutrition context
and also five percent of your potassium
as well believe it or not the blend
actually has some meat in it well rather
Animal product that is not just whey you
got whey isolate and way concentrate yes
but also some bone broth and egg white
protein and pea protein eye slip so
that's going to give you a whole lot of
different amino acids it does mean this
is not vegetarian friendly if that's
important to you and there's also like
several different forms of fiber in here
like oat bran fiber and carb 10 pea
starch which is also a pretty fiber
heavy product here you've got 18 of
recommended intake of fiber per serving
with a nice five grams unless you're
getting a really good balance of
different forms approaching different
sources of protein which is often really
important for people who are either
looking to bulk or simply trying to have
like the most complete approach to the
nutrition as possible getting good
amount of carbohydrates too so as long
as you're not in an unbelievably low
carb or low fat diet this is a really
filling and tasty way to get some extra
protein in your diet next up another
question we get asked a lot is the best
protein powder for women now to be
honest it's not really a good reason to
gender these sorts of products
nonetheless our female readers they tend
to gravitate toward the protein from
Legion plus a couple of reasons for that
uh number one is there's no fat here
whatsoever so if you're in a low-fat
diet a low calorie diet this is going to
fit really easily into that also it's
also natural it's an all-natural product
you also tends to be popular among our
female readers so this is naturally
flavored and sweetened there's also
grass-fed Dairy and these ones are from
Ireland but the main reason is the
flavors aren't too weird they've got a
lot of really interesting tasty flavors
it's not super common for for a protein
powder company even a popular one to
have more than a few flavors this one
has 13 different flavors so here you've
got a really cool one strawberry and
banana which we've tried before down
here we've got the cinnamon cereal which
are big fans of there's a mocha
cappuccino there's cookies and cream
there's all these more dare I see
approachable flavors that sound to a lot
of people a bit more fun to eat or to
consume rather than just your straight
regular chocolate and vanilla I'm a big
fan of vanilla myself I'm not against
companies that just have vanilla and
chocolate but certainly we find that our
female readers they are more interested
in a company that has a wider variety of
flavors like this one but you know so am
I the last protein powder we're going to
put on this list is dymatizes ISO 104
the best hydrolyzed whey protein powder
product earlier you might remember me
talking about hydrolyzer whey protein
saying that it absorbs more quickly than
other forms of whey protein but it's
typically prohibitively expensive and
not very tasty but diametize is done
it's produced a very cost effective
product that's because they combine
hydrolyzed way and weight isolate so
that saves him a bit of money but
hydrolyzed weight is still the number
one ingredient on the ingredients list
it is more height less weight than
weight isolate so this is still
definitely a solid hydrolyzed whey
product it's pretty cost effective as
well it's a dollar 40 per scoop this has
also been certified by informed Choice
which means they've been tested for
banned substances so that's gonna be a
good use for a competitive athlete
especially because it's competitive
athletes who are the most likely to find
benefit from high glasway protein
products finally it tastes really good
there aren't that many project patterns
out there that taste good with water and
I think Iceland honey has done a good
job of it they also have a cinnamon bun
flavor or cinnamon roll flavor which
we've tried before mixed with whole milk
it is a diet for they've done a pretty
impressive thing at dymatized by making
a hydrolyze away product that doesn't
break the bank and also tastes pretty
darn good so that does it for our list
or the best way protein powders and some
non-way protein powders as well we have
really gone through a lot of tubs the
bobbin office landing on this list and
we're pretty confident in these picks
the way we land on these picks by the
way there are a lot of areas to look at
when analog sizing a protein powder but
like the number one has been protein per
calorie because that's a priority for a
lot of folks they want to avoid extra
carbs and fat but also the ingredients
list themselves like the form of whey
again whey isolate tends out the best
balance approach per calorie and taste
and affordability we concentrate does
tend to taste a little bit better and we
have no issue with that if like the
customer doesn't mind that as well so
it's really up to you as to what you're
prioritizing if it's protein per calorie
if it's flavor and also additives and
extra ingredients the obvious one here
is that there are a lot of natural
flavored and naturally sweetened protein
powder and a lot of artificially
flavored and artificially sweetened ones
candidly the artificially flavored and
sweetened ones tend to taste a bit
better like by and large but of course
plenty of people would rather stick to
naturally flavored and sweetened ones so
we pointed those out so we're really
we're talking about protein per calorie
we're talking about the form of whey
protein use the additives the extra
ingredients and how natural and
artificial it is finally the presence of
soy is one that's important to a lot of
folks again soy lecithin is pretty
common in a lot of protein powders
because it helps with mixability but
there are minority of folks who are
concerned that soy lecithin is going to
somehow affect their estrogen levels it
won't encourage you to look at a 20
minute long video that I did on this
channel a while back analyzing this
claim but nonetheless the conclusion I'm
trying to reach here is that the right
protein powder for you depends entirely
on your own preferences be it natural be
it artificial be it flavor be
approaching a calorie and so on so find
out what you want from a protein powder
and then you're going to find what you
need on this list so that's it for our
video I'm glad you've watched if you
want to again see the full written
version of this video you can just
Google it go bar band best way protein
powders and uh it'll pop right up and
otherwise stick around hope to see the
next video
foreign